Gigina Rajesh

Software Engineer - Front End

Giginacleetus18@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/gigina-rajesh14 www.gigina.info +44 7417415633 Tonbridge, England, TN9 1NZ, UK

Front-End Software Engineer with 5+ years of experience creating responsive and user-friendly web applications. Skilled in front end developing technologies and modern frameworks with a keen eye for design and usability. A collaborative team player who communicates effectively with designers, back-end developers, and stakeholders to drive project success. Proactive in learning emerging technologies and industry best practices to continuously improve code quality and user experience.

Work Experience

Software Engineer - Front End

Jan 2023 - Sep 2024

Adox Global

- Created and implemented more than 7 interactive web application pages utilizing HTML5 and CSS3, resulting in a 30% increase in user retention rates and a more intuitive navigation experience for end-users.
- Leveraged modern technologies in collaboration with UX/UI designers to translate design pattern into high quality code.
- Exhibited strong Client Facing capabilities in gathering requirements, managing expectations, and delivery processes of top-
- Developed new Angular components for customer facing applications, improving the average user time on page by 2 minutes.
- Constructed user-friendly web application pages with JavaScript and CSS frameworks; achieved cross browser compatibility, enhancing accessibility for over 8, 000 unique visitors each month while increasing overall site traffic by 20%.

SharePoint Developer

Oct 2019 - Sep 2020

JoulestoWatts Business Solution Pvt.Ltd

Expertly used the Front-End coding tools Such as HTML, CSS and JavaScript Frameworks to design and customize more than 10 SharePoint web pages, web parts, and lists in a successful manner.

- · Managed and maintained more than 15 SharePoint lists data web applications by efficiently performing
- JQuery REST APIs.
- Enhanced customer experience engagement by 10% through migration of a multi-page UX into a single page app.
- Executed SDLC best practices within the Agile environment to bring rapid iterations for clients.

Technology Consultant

Aug 2018 - Oct 2019

Ernst & Young Global Delivery Services India LLP

- Spearheaded more than 5 SharePoint portals, including translating wireframe designs into functional web applications by using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, React and NodeJS with 100% client satisfaction.
- Achieved 95% unit testing success rate by supporting continuous interaction between users, development, and QA teams throughout the SDLC.
- Identified and fixed bugs from existing websites and incorporated creative enhancements that successfully improved functionality and efficiency by 25%.
- Executed the best practices attention to detail in each project using strong communication skills and management skills and to collaborate efficiently within development team to meet project deadlines.

Junior Software Developer

Sep 2016 - Dec 2017

Softonix Technologies

- Used PHP, MySQL, JavaScript to code and deploy more than 7 MVC web applications.
- Worked closely with an agile team of 10 members and provided end to end solutions for clients.

- Built the next version of client web application to add new user designs and features using native Javascript and in-house framework, reducing reported bug issues by over 15%.
- Implemented advanced Technical Skills to troubleshoot and resolve complex front end issues, improving website performance by 50%.

Core Skills

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript / Typescript, Jquery, Bootstrap, SharePoint, PHP, Git, C#, SQL, Tailwind CSS, OOP, React, SEO, AngularJS, SASS, ECMAScript 2015, JIRA, AWS, Github, Node JS

Education

University of East London, UK

Jan 2021 - Jul 2022

MSc Computer Science

Marian Engineering College, India

Aug 2012 - May 2016

BTech Computer Science and Engineering

Certificates

Career Essentials in Generative AI

Nov 2024

Microsoft and Linkedin

Career Essentials in Software Development

May 2024

Microsoft and Linkedin

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Cloud Foundations

Mar 2021

Amazon Web Services Training and Certification